<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://wanstin.github.io</id>
    <title>Wanstin</title>
    <updated>2020-04-08T13:05:08.002Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://wanstin.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://wanstin.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>欲买桂花同载酒，终不似，少年游</subtitle>
    <logo>https://wanstin.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://wanstin.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2020, Wanstin</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The great success story]]></title>
        <id>https://wanstin.github.io/post/the-great-success-story/</id>
        <link href="https://wanstin.github.io/post/the-great-success-story/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-04-08T13:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn’t have a rich father.Tried 3 times for university.All failed.I applied for Harvard for 10 times.All failed.They don’t even want to see me. For the last time,I went to the teacher’s college which was considered the third or fourth class of my city. So I applied jobs for 30 times.Got rejected.It was so difficult at that time,I was so frustrated,because I taught in the university.My pay was 10 dollars a month.Because I could not find a good job. In 1994,discussed that I’m going to do something called Internet and 23 of them against it,they said “This is a stupid idea,we have never heard about the Internet,and you know nothing about computer.”  And I never thought I was smart.Nobody believed that I could be successful.Because everybody said. ”This guy think differently,think crazily.You know,they think about something that never work.” I tried to borrow 3 thousands US dollars from the banks.It took me three month but I still can not get it. We talk to over 30 or 40 venture capitalists. Everybody said no,forget it.  Lot of people said Alibaba is a terrible model. As I said, I believe it , I think this thing could be big.I never thought it could be that big like today! I believed something, something is waiting for me there and I have to work hard to prove myself. That was a tough experience.So,we gathered 50 thousands US dollars from 18 founders. We started.  For the first three years,we didn’t have even 1 dollar revenue from our business.It was not easy.But why it kepts us going ahead,going forward, because I received lots of email of thanks from our customers.They say : “This is such a great thing.We cannot pay you but this thing helped us.If you keep on helping us,one day you will be successful and I believed this.”  Little by little,we built up our business.Little by little,we built up our ecosystem of the infrastructure.And now after 16 years,we have Alibaba group,we have Tmall group,we have Taobao group , we have Alipay.And people said : ”You are so smart.How could you make a company like that?”  Bill Gates,Warren Buffet,Jack Weich,Larry Page,Mark Zuckerberg, the difference between those people and other people.They are always optimistic for the future. They never complain ,they always try to solve the problems of the others.When you optimistic,it’s always opportunity.People say the same thing here today. “Jack,where is the opportunity? ” “I don’t have a job.I don’t have this. I don’t have that.”  We are at the best time of this century.The best assets you have is that you’re young.Don’t complain.Let the other people complain.The opportunity always lies where people complain.Think about how you can make things different. Is there anythings I can do that makes the difference ? And then when you think about this,start to do it.I saw a lot of people,young people have fantastic ideas every evening.But in the morning ,they got to the office same again. Being entrepreneur,you have to do the things before the other people do.You have to wake up before the other people wake up. You have to be more brave than the others.  Use your instinct.Everything you do is to the need of the customer. To everybody,to any person,tomorrow is new.Make the move.Make the action.Whether investors believe it or not , whether your friends believe it or not , whether your parents believe it or not. That’s not important.You believe it,your team believe it and work day and night on this.That’s how the things happens.Make enough mistakes,You fail .You stand up.Any mistake is an income, is a wonderful revenue.  Don’t worry about the money, money follows the people.People should follow their dreams.If you have a dream,just go ahead.I think nobody can conquer the world.We only can serve the world.Either work for the others or work for yourself , and I choose the way of working for myself. Working for myself that means work for the society.If really want to work for yourself , think about the others.Because only when the other people are successful,when the other people are happy.You will be successful,you will be happy.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[快捷键]]></title>
        <id>https://wanstin.github.io/post/kuai-jie-jian/</id>
        <link href="https://wanstin.github.io/post/kuai-jie-jian/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-03-29T12:39:15.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>文本操作（通用）</strong>：<br>
1.Ctrl+C = 复制<br>
2.Ctrl+V = 粘贴<br>
3.Ctrl+A = 全选<br>
4.Ctrl+X = 剪切<br>
5.Ctrl+Z = 撤回<br>
6.Ctrl+Shift+R = 选中整块<br>
7.End = 光标跳到行尾<br>
8.Home = 光标跳到行首<br>
9.Shift+Home = 选中从当前光标位置到这一行的行首<br>
10.Shift+End = 选中从当前光标位置到这一行的行尾</p>
<p><strong>Windows常用快捷键</strong>：<br>
1.F3 = 打开资源管理器搜索结果<br>
2.F11 = 最大化文件显示/恢复正常显示<br>
3.Win+E = 打开&quot;我的电脑&quot;<br>
4.Win+W = 关闭当前窗口<br>
5.Win+R = 打开运行窗口<br>
6.Win+D = 最小化所有窗口，显示桌面<br>
7.Win+L = 锁定计算机，回到登录窗口<br>
8.Win+M = 最小化当前窗口<br>
9.Win+U = 打开设置<br>
10.Win+Home = 将正在使用之外的所有其他窗口最小化<br>
11.Win+break = 打开控制面板系统属性<br>
12.Win+↑/↓/←/→ = 窗口位置<br>
13.Ctrl+F = 查找（各种编辑器也通用）<br>
14.Ctrl+D = 将选定项目至回收站<br>
15.Ctrl+Shift+Esc = 打开资源管理器搜索当前页面<br>
16.Ctrl+Shift+N = 新建文件<br>
17.Alt+Tab = 切换至上个窗口<br>
18.Alt+Enter = 打开选中项属性<br>
19.Alt+F4 = 关闭当前程序</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>